<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sanjaybalaji.dev</title>
    <link>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on sanjaybalaji.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:47:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanjaybalaji.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building smaller docker images — the right way</title>
      <link>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/posts/2022/08/building-smaller-docker-images-the-right-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:47:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/posts/2022/08/building-smaller-docker-images-the-right-way/</guid>
      <description>Docker images are great, they are easy to work with — but they can get blown up to huge sizes when you are not paying attention on building them right.
Apart from just the size, this can also end up bringing a serious security vulnerability to your production Kubernetes cluster just because you had a package that you never used.
Section 3 is a must read if you have a large python app docker image that needs to be optimised and made smaller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Kubernetes cluster on AWS using kops</title>
      <link>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/posts/2022/08/creating-a-kubernetes-cluster-on-aws-using-kops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:47:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/posts/2022/08/creating-a-kubernetes-cluster-on-aws-using-kops/</guid>
      <description>This article will help you to set up a Kubernetes cluster on AWS using kops. A command-line utility that helps you create your own master and worker nodes on AWS.
The Major difference from using the eksctl is — eksctl uses the EKS managed service that manages the master nodes for you, but here you manage the master nodes as well.
Requirements a free-tier AWS account on which your user has the necessary permissions on IAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:27:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/projects/</guid>
      <description>Food Delivery Web App Responsive Web App that is used to manage orders and navigate delivery executives to multiple drop-offs. Postgres DB, Deployed on Heroku Cloud Built using Flask for a business in the United States. URL Shortener Web URL shortner built using Redis and Flask. Deployed on Heroku Cloud. More Projects to be added soon </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:20:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a DevOps engineer.
I like to automate things and read articles.
Interested in the block chain and cryptocurrencies.
I like to go for long drives, take pictures and sleep in.
Contact You can email me at balz.sanjay@gmail.com
You can find my posts at https://buggycodemaster.medium.com/ or in the r/posts section of this website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senior DevOps Engineer</title>
      <link>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/timeline/tellius-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/timeline/tellius-devops/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Working on automating the Tellius app stack with terraform, to be compatible across all 3 major cloud providers. Working on building CI/CD pipelines using Drone CI and Argo CD. Implementing Istio and other tools for improved security. Managing &amp;amp; tracking compliance of our application deployments using Vanta. Working on managing KOPS clusters. Working on cost optimization in the cloud. Recognition Received the Innovation award within 3 months of joining Tellius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Reliability Engineer</title>
      <link>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/timeline/eightfold-sre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/timeline/eightfold-sre/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Worked on writing python APIs to utilize AWS Boto SDKs for our internal tooling applications. Worked on Cloudformation templates to deploy app stacks across regions. Worked on assisting with developer productivity for internal tooling and automation. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud DevOps Engineer 1 &amp; 2</title>
      <link>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/timeline/oracle-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/timeline/oracle-devops/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Worked on dockerizing applications, deploying to kubernetes. Scaled traditional applications and figured out a deployment plan for monoliths to make them fault-tolerant and highly available. Worked with Product teams to build out and deploy applications to Oracle Cloud Infrastructure. Helped build cross-region disaster recovery systems and SOPs across Canada &amp;amp; Australia. Recognition Rated Outstanding Employee every year during my tenure at Oracle. Won multiple awards at the Quarterly Awards Ceremony for Innovation and Drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internship</title>
      <link>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/timeline/internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanjaybalaji.dev/timeline/internship/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Worked extensively on Docker and Jenkins, to setup CI/CD pipelines.
Worked with for a Java 8 application that would internally use Kubernetes SDKs to deploy and manage customer environments on K8s Clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
